CHAPTER 22 WHEN THE SUN WENT DOWN When his head was out of sight
Colin turned to Mary. "Go and meet him," he said; and Mary flew across the grass to
the door under the ivy. Dickon was watching him with sharp eyes. There were
scarlet spots on his cheeks and he looked amazing, but he showed no signs of
falling. "I can stand," he said, and his head was still held up and he said it quite
grandly. "I told thee the could as soon as the stop being afraid," answered Dickon and th
stopped." "Yes, I've stopped," said Colin. Then suddenly he remembered something Mary
had said. "Are you making Magic?" he asked sharply dickens's curly mouth spread in
a cheerful grin th doing Magic thy cell he said it same Magic has made these ear
work out of the earth," and he touched with his thick boot a clump of crocuses in the
grass. Colin looked down at them I he said slowly, "there couldn't be bigger Magic
then that there— —there couldn't be." He drew himself up straighter than ever. "I'm
going to walk to that tree," he said, pointing to one a few feet away from him.
"I'm going to be standing when weather STS comes here. I can rest against the
tree if I like. When I want to sit down I
will sit down, but not before. Bring a rug from the chair." He walked to the tree and
though Dickon held his arm he was wonderfully steady. When he stood against
the tree trunk it was not too plain that he supported himself against it, and he
still held himself so straight that he looked tall. When Ben weather staff came
through the door in the wall he saw him standing there and he heard Mary
muttering something under her breath. "What art saying he asked rather
testily because he did not want his attention distracted from the long thin
straight boy figure and proud face. But she did not tell him. What she was saying was
this: "You can do it! You can do it! I told
you you could! You can do it! You you can do it! You
can She was saying it to Colin because she wanted to make Magic and keep him on
his feet looking like that. She could not bear that he should give in before Ben
weather staff He did not give in. She was uplifted by a sudden feeling that he
looked quite beautiful in spite of his thinness. He fixed his eyes on Ben
Weatherstaff in his funny imperious way.
"Look at me!" he commanded. "Look at me all over! Am I a hunchback? Have I got crooked
legs?" Ben weather staff had not quite got over his emotion, but he had recovered a
little and answered almost in his usual way. "Not th he said now to the sort.
What's thou been doing with thy cell Hiding out of sight and letting folk
think thou was and half witted half witted said Colin angrily. "Who
thought that?" "Lots of fools," said Ben the world's full of jackasses Bray in and
they never brain out but lies. What did thou shut thyself up
for everyone thought I was going to die," said Colin shortly. "I'm not!" And he said
it with such decision Ben weather staff looked him over, up and down, down and up
th die!" he said with dry exaltation now to the sort that's got too much luck in
thee. When I see thee put thy legs on the
ground in such a hurry I know that was
all right. Sit thee down on the rug a bit young me and give me thy
orders." There was a queer mixture of crabbed tenderness and shrewd understanding in his
manner. Mary had poured out speech as rapidly as she could as they had come
down the Long Walk. The chief thing to be remembered, she had told him, was that
Colin was getting well— —getting well. The garden was doing it. No one must
let him remember about having humps and dying. The Raja condescended to seat
himself on a rug under the tree. "What work do you do in the gardens weather staff he
inquired anything I'm told to do," answered old Ben. "I'm kept on by favor—
—because she liked me." "She?" said Colin their mother answer answered Ben weather
staff My mother?" said Colin, and he looked about him quietly. "This was her garden,
wasn't it I it was that!" and Ben weathera looked about him too. "She were main fond
of it." "It is my garden now, I am fond of
it. I shall come here every day," announced Colin. "But it is to be a secret. My orders
are that no one is to know that we come here. Dickon and my cousin have worked
and made it come alive. I shall send for you sometimes to help— —but you must come
when no one can see you." Ben Weatherstaff's face twisted itself in a dry old
smile. "I've come here before when no one saw me," he said. "What!" exclaimed Colin. "When
the last time I was here," rubbing his chin and looking round, "was about 2 year'
ago but But no one has been in it for 10
years!" cried Colin. "There was no door!" "I'm no one," said old Ben dry and I didn't
come through the door. I come over the wall the rheumatics held me back the last 2
years that come and did a bit of pruning cried Dickon. "I couldn't make out how it
had been done." "She was so fond of it— —she was!" said Ben Weatherstaff slowly
and she was such a pretty young thing.
She says to me once, 'Ben,' says she laughing if ever I'm ill or if I go away
you must take care of my roses.' When she did go away the orders was no one was
ever to come nigh. But I come," with grumpy obstinacy. "Over the wall I come— —until the
Rheumatic stopped me and I did a bit of work once a year. She'd gave her order
first." "It wouldn't have been as wick as it is if thou hadn't done it," said Dickon.
"I did wonder." "I'm glad you did it weather staff said Colin. "You'll know how to keep the
secret I I'll know, sir," answered Ben and it'll be easier for a man with
rheumatics to come in at the door." On the grass near the tree Mary had dropped her
Trel Colin stretched out his hand and took it up. An odd expression expression
came into his face and he began to scratch at the
earth. His thin hand was weak enough but presently as they watched him— —Mary with
quite breathless interest— —he drove the end of the Trel into the soil and turned some
over. "You can do it! You can do it!" said Mary to herself. "I tell you, you can
dickens's round eyes were full of eager curiousness but he said not a word.
Ben Weatherstaff looked on with interested face. Colin persevered. After he had turned a few
Trel fulls of soil he spoke exultantly to Dickon in his best
Yorkshire th said as that have me walking about here same as other folk
and they said they'd have me digging I thought they was just leing to please me.
This is only the first day and I've walked and here I am digging Ben Weatherstaff's mouth fell
open again when he heard him, but he ended by chuckling. "Eh!" he said, "that
sounds as if that'd got wits in now thought a Yorkshire lad for sure and not
digging too how' th like to plant a bit
of something I can get the a rose in a pot." "Go and get it!" said Colin, digging
excitedly. "Quick!
Quick!" It was done quickly enough indeed.
Ben weather staff went his way for getting rheumatics. Dickon took his spade
and dug the hole deeper and WI wider than a new digger with thin white hands
could make it. Mary slipped out to run and bring back a watering can When
Dickon had deepened the hole Colin went on turning the soft earth over and over.
He looked up at the sky, flushed and glowing with the strangely new exercise,
slight as it was. "I want to do it before the sun goes quite— —quite down," he
said. Mary thought that perhaps the sun held back a few few minutes just on
purpose. Ben Weatherstaff brought the rose in its pot from the
greenhouse. He hobbled over the grass as fast as he could. He had begun to be
excited, too. He knelt down by the hole and broke the pot from the mold Here, lad,"
he said, handing the plant to Colin. "Set it in the earth thy cell same as the
king does when he goes to a new place." The thin white hands shook a
little and Colin's flush grew deeper as he set the rose in the mold and held it
while old Ben made firm the earth. It was filled in and pressed down and made
steady. Mary was leaning forward on her hands and knees. Soot had flown down and
marched forward to see what was being done. Nut and Shell chattered about it from a cherry
tree It's planted!" said Colin at last. "And the sun is only slipping over the edge.
Help me up, Dickon. I want to be standing when it goes. That's part of the Magic."
And Dickon helped him, and the Magic— —or whatever it was— —so gave him strength
that when the sun did slip over the edge and end the strange lovely afternoon for
them there he actually stood on his two feet